What's slower than a speeding bullet, and able to
hit tall buildings at a single bound?
Airplane! is a comedy film directed by Jim Abrahams.
An ex-fighter pilot forced to take over the controls of an airliner
when the flight crew succumbs to food poisoning.
Ted Striker, played by Robert Hays.
Elaine Dickinson, played by Julie Hagerty.
Dr. Rumack, played by Leslie Nielsen.
Roger Murdock, played by Kareem Abdul-Jabbar.
Steve McCroskey, played by Lloyd Bridges.
Capt. Clarence Oveur, played by Peter Graves.
(alternatively titled Flying High!) is a 1980 American comedy film written and directed by David Zucker,
Jim Abrahams, and Jerry Zucker in their directorial debut, and produced by Jon Davison.
It stars Robert Hays and Julie Hagerty and features Leslie Nielsen, Robert Stack,
Lloyd Bridges, Peter Graves, Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, and Lorna Patterson.
It is a parody of the disaster film genre, particularly the 1957 Paramount film Zero
Hour!, from which it borrows the plot, central characters, and some dialogue.
It also draws many elements from Airport 1975 and
other films in the Airport series.
It is known for using surreal humor and fast-paced slapstick comedy, including visual
and verbal puns, gags, running jokes, and satirical sharp overtones.
Released by Paramount Pictures, it was a critical and commercial success,
grossing $171 million worldwide against a budget of $3.5 million.
The creators received the Writers Guild of America Award for Best Adapted Comedy, and nominations for the Golden
Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy and for the BAFTA Award for Best Screenplay.
Since its release, the film's reputation has grown substantially, and Airplane!
is now considered one of the greatest comedy films ever made, inspiring numerous
references, homages, and further parodies in popular culture.
It ranked sixth on Bravo's 100 Funniest Movies.
In a 2007 survey by Channel 4 in the United Kingdom, it was judged the
second-greatest comedy of all time, behind Monty Python's Life of Brian.
In 2008, it was selected by Empire magazine as one of the 500 Greatest Movies of All Time,
and in 2012 was voted number one on the 50 Funniest Comedies Ever poll.
In 2010, Airplane!
was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of
Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, post-traumatic
stress disorder (ptsd), airplane, cataclysm, nun.
The tone is lighthearted.